JOANA DE **OLIVEIRA VIEIRA**



GRAPHIC / WEB DESIGNER

PERSONAL INFO

Birthday:

21 February 1994

Nationality:

Portuguese

Languages:

- Portuguese (native)
- English (C1)

Address:

Rua Verde Pinho nº 147 2ºDrt Coimbra, Portugal

Phone:

(+351) 965 661 955

Email:

joanaoliveiravieira@gmail.com

Website:

joanavieira.github.io

Driving License:

Hobbies:



I'm a passionate board game player.



I like sewing and creating keychains for people to



Enjoy going to dance classes.



Love playing story driven video games.

ABOUT

I'm a Graphic/Web Designer with great experience in multimedia and print design and a passion for Front-End development. Quick learner and hard worker, always aiming to improve through feedback. Collaborative team player always cheerful and willing to learn, accustomed to performing in deadline-driven environments.

Currently responsible for the institutional design of Cáritas Coimbra and its 90 centres, actively collaborating in the design of national and international projects in which Cáritas Coimbra is involved.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer, 2018 - Present

Cáritas de Coimbra (Portugal)

Currently working in the Innovation Department at Cáritas Coimbra, being responsible for the management of social media, supporting national and international projects in wich Cáritas is involved, producing graphic, multimedia and communication materials such as:

PRINT

- · Brochures & Flyers
- · Logos
- Posters & Cards
- Roll-ups
- Templates
- Stationery

WEB & MULTIMEDIA

- Newsletters
- Campaigns
- · Website Management
- Video Editing
- · Social Media
- · Animated Banners

PHOTOGRAPHY

- Retouching
- · Photo Editing

EU PROJECTS

- · Social Media KPI's
- Design

In 2019 Cáritas Coimbra had a 42% grow in the production of multimedia and graphic materials (developed 210+ graphic/multimedia projects).

Internship | Graphic Designer, 2017 - 2018

Cáritas de Coimbra (Portugal)

Intern in the Innovation Department at Cáritas Coimbra, learning the company values and mission, where I worked closely with the innovation team in the production of print and multimedia items.

Launched and managed new social media platforms for Cáritas Coimbra (Youtube, Linkedin, Twitter).

Summer Internship | UX/UI Designer, Jun 2016 - Sep 2016

Faber Ventures (Lisbon, Portugal)

Faber Ventures Summer Internship which consisted of 4 days a week working as a design intern, designing user interfaces for mobile and web applications and 1 day a week learning how technology startups work and, at the same time, understand the process of designing innovative products.

· Worked with a interdisciplinary team to develop the product Glick (financial app that gives personalizes suggestions based on the user's spending habits), presented at Microsoft.

SKILLS

DESIGN



SOFTWARE

Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Adobe Indesign Adobe Premiere • • • • • • • • Sketch InVision Balsamiq Git Microsoft Office

PROGRAMMING

HTML5	•••••
CSS3	•••••
Bootstrap	•••••
Foundation	•••••
JQuery	• • • • • • •
Javascript	• • • • • • •
Wordpress	• • • • • • •

COLLABORATION

Flexible	•••••
Communicative	•••••
Teamwork	•••••
Active Listening	•••••
Problem-solving	• • • • • • •

EDUCATION

Sep 12 - Oct 16

Degree in Design and Multimedia

University of Coimbra (Portugal)

Sep 02 - Jul 12

Visual Arts Course

Quinta das Flores Secondary School (Coimbra, Portugal)

AFFILIATIONS

Oct 15 - Feb 18

Member and Collaborator of the Technology Department

Resistance Junior Company (Coimbra, Portugal) | facebook.com/resistanceje

Collaborated in the creation of recruitment campaigns and advertisements of the company's workshops and activities.

- · Collaborated on the redesign of the resistance's website.
- · Participated on the project "Já é Queima?" (website/app with a countdown to the traditional festivity of the students of Coimbra and and during the festival, the website displays the event schedule, prices, etc...).

Oct 15 - Jun 16

Youth Group Coordinator

ex aequo Coimbra (Coimbra, Portugal) | rea.pt

Coordinated bimonthly meetings for the ex aequo Coimbra lgbt youth group.

- Participated in the 23rd Youth Group Coordinators Training.
- Planned and hosted meetings twice a month.
- Welcoming of new members .

Oct 15 - Jun 16

Member of the Design Department

Informatics Engineering Student Nucleus of UC (Coimbra, Portugal) | nei.dei.uc.pt

Designed posters for the nucleus activities and helped with the organization of events.

PARTICIPATIONS

2019

Mentor on the Hack for Good Challenge in partnership with Caloust Gulbenkian

Hackathon Shift APPens (Coimbra, Portugal) | shiftappens.com

Mentor in the Hack for Good Challenges, where I gave feedback to the participants on the design of their projects, based on the experience acquired at Cáritas de Coimbra working with national and international projects in the area of active ageing.

2016

Conference attendee

Mirror Conf (Braga, Portugal) | 2016.mirrorconf.com

2016

Volunteer (Organization Support)

National Design Students Meeting (Coimbra, Portugal) | 2016.ened.pt

2016

Hackathon participant

Hackathon Shift APPens (Coimbra, Portugal) | 2016.shiftappens.com/hangover

Developed the project "Slice" - web tool for organisation and division of monetary funds.